CURRICULUM VITAE



SANJIT PANDIT, C. Eng, MIE (I), MAusIMM

GSM: +968 7175 5450

Email: panditsanjit@yahoo.com

Date of Birth : 20th April 1971 Age : 47 Years Nationality : Indian

Educational Qualifications : Degree in Mining Engineering,

: Post Graduate Diploma in Business Management.

Marital Status : Married, blessed with a daughter and a son

Present Location : Sohar, Sultanate of Oman

KEY SKILLS:

Mining Engineering, Exploration Program Management, Rock Blasting Technique, Mining Operations, Mining Investment Analysis and Feasibility Study.

PERSONAL STATEMENT:

A seasoned Chartered Mining Engineer supported with Postgraduate in Business Management qualifications with strong background in the operational, technical and commercial aspects of mining business with a demonstrated capacity for mining investment analysis plus 22 years of experience in the mining industry domain.

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCES:

Serving as an internal consultant in mining expertise and sharing knowledge with colleagues for the captive chrome mining business for the company. Responsible for strategic planning of captive mines, lead the mining business development and integration of chrome ore supply to the ferrochrome plant for use.

Conducted fundamental research and gather pool of information to prospect chromite ore mining investments opportunities by networking with governmental, industrial and other sources of market intelligence. The potential assets are predominately at exploration through to feasibility stage. Estimated OPEX and CAPEX in accordance with mining plans and analyzed manpower needs, requirement of HEMM equipment and prepare financial models for mining.

Develop detailed exploration strategy and supervise of all exploration program activities, review geological maps and drilling logs to estimate quality and quantity of chrome ore deposit. Evaluate the project's economic merits, conduct feasibility studies and align to mining operating goals.

Conducted, cash flow analysis of potential deposits based on ore reserve data, production estimate, potential risk assessment and worked with internal colleagues to close the deals.

Perform all necessary administration including staff selection, training and development, annual budget preparation, financial administration, planning, organizing and scheduling works.

Oversee the development and completion of Exploration Study Report for submission to Public Authority for Mining, Environmental Management Plan for Ministry of Environment and Climate Affairs and project construction for further Greenfield mining operation.

Good understanding of rock blasting technique, blast design and technical services, fragmentation analysis, ground vibration monitoring and control blasting.

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

: Post Graduate Diploma in Business Management (PGDBM)

Symbiosis Institute of Business Management | India,

2011

: Bachelor of Engineering in Mining

Bengal Engineering College, University of Calcutta | India

1995

PROFESSIONAL MEMBETSHIPS

: Member (MIE) and Chartered Mining Engineer (India),

Institution of Engineers (India), Membership No. M-1569435.

: Member (MAusIMM),

Australasian Institute of Mining and Metallurgy, Australia,

Membership No. 330322.

: Fellow Member and Approved Valuer - Mines & Quarry,

Institution of Valuers, India, Membership No. 27370.

: Institute of Explosive Engineers, United Kingdom

Membership No. IM 2920.

CAREER HISTORY

May, 2017 – Present : **Mining Engineer**,

Al Tamman Indsil Ferrochrome LLC (ATIFC), Muscat

Overseas Group | Sohar, Oman.

ATIFC is a 50:50 Joint Venture company of Muscat Overseas Group and Indsil Group of India. The company was setup with the objective to tap the potential of Oman Chrome Ore reserve by establishing a

\$50 million Ferro Chrome Plant, an upstream facility to manufacture value added products i.e. ferrochrome. ATIFC commissioned two numbers of submerged arc furnaces of 24 MVA capacity each with installed capacity of smelting plant is 75,000 MTPA high carbon ferrochrome products. ATIFC uses around 15,000 MT per month of Chromite Ore for production of ferrochrome. Recently, ATIFC has signed an agreement with Sohar Free Zone for the expansion of the company's existing plant. The upcoming project that will have an additional increase production capacity of 37,500 MTPA with construction of two more 24 MVA capacity furnaces.

Aug. 2012 – July, 2016 : **Operations Manager**,

Bahar Oman Metals & Allied Services LLC, OMZEST Group |

Muscat, Oman.

The company was a part of Bahar Oman Holding LLC, a Joint Venture between Omar Zawawi Establishment (OMZEST) and International Minerals Resources B.V. (IMR BV), one of the world's largest private mining and metals investment groups based in Amsterdam, the Netherlands. BOMAS was responsible for captive Chromite ore mining in Oman as well as abroad for the proposed \$150 million Ferro Chrome Plant.

Feb. 2008 – July, 2012 : Blasting Engineer/Project Manager,

Technical Services & Rock Blasting Co. LLC (Techrock), Al Fajar Al Alamia Co. (SAOG) Group | Muscat, Oman.

The parent company is engaged in the manufacturing/sales of explosive and trading of related ancillary products and Techrock a sister company is engaged in rock drilling/blasting services in Oman. Clients included quarry operators, cement companies, seismic exploration companies and contractors employed in public works such as road construction, pipeline, tunneling and underwater excavation.

Aug, 2006 – Dec. 2007 : **Mining Engineer**,

Qatar Quarry Co. LLC, Lafarge Group | Qatar.

The company is active in quarrying and sales of aggregate, armor rock in Qatar.

May, 2001 – July, 2005 : Sales Engineer/Asst. Sales Manager,

IDL Explosives Ltd. (Formally Gulf Oil Corporation Ltd.)

Hyderabad, India.

The IDL Explosives Limited manufacturers, sales and distribute industrial explosive products and initiation system in pan India for mining and civil construction industries. The Company has been an industry leader for 50 years. It is a 100% wholly owned subsidiary of the Gulf Oil Corporation Limited and a part of the global Hinduja Group which has diversified business interests.

July, 1995 – Mar. 2001 : Graduate Engineer Trainee/Mining Engineer,

Ferro Alloys Corporation Ltd | Bhadrak, Orissa, India.

The Company is one of the India's largest and established producers and exporters of High Carbon Ferro Chrome/Charge Chrome Metal worldwide and engaged in mining to beneficiation of chrome ore from open pit to underground mines.

PRESENT ADDRESS : Plant: Plot No. 3490, Free Zone Sohar,

P.O. Box 592, Hamriya, Postal Code: 131,

Sultanate of Oman.

LINKEDIN PROFILE : www.linkedin.com/in/sanjit-pandit-mausimm-9a8aaa22/